Here we in the lesson map, just as a reminder.
这里是课程地图 首先提示一下
We need the process covariance matrix to model the stochastic
我们需要过程协方差矩阵对状态转换函数的
part of the state transition function.
随机部分建模
First I'm going to show you how the acceleration is expressed by
首先 我向你展示如何使用动力学方程
the kinematic equations.
表达加速度
And then I'm going to use that information to derive the process
然后 我会使用该信息来推导出
covariance matrix Q.
过程协方差矩阵 Q
Say we have two consecutive observations of the same pedestrian with initial and
假设对于同一个行人 我们有两次连续观察
final velocities.
获得了初始速度和最终速度
&gt;From the kinematic formulas we can derive the current position and
- 根据动力学公式 我们可以推导出当前位置
speed as a function of previous state variables, including
和速度 与上一次测量的状态变量
the change in the velocity or in other words, including the acceleration.
(包括速度变化率，也就是加速度)之间的函数关系
You can see how this is derived below.
你可以在下面看到推导过程
Looking at the deterministic part of our motion model,
看看下面运动模型的确定部分
we assume the velocity is constant.
我们假设速度恒定
However, in reality the pedestrian speed might change.
但是 现实中 行人速度可能变化
Since the acceleration is unknown, we can add it to the noise component.
由于加速度未知 我们可以把它加到误差分量中
And this random noise would be expressed analytically as in the last terms in
这里的随机误差可以表示为
the equation.
方程中的最后一项
So, we have a random acceleration vector in this form,
因此，这里有一个随机加速度向量
which is described by a 0 mean and the covariance matrix, Q.
它的均值是0，协方差矩阵用 Q 表示
Delta t is computed at each Kalman filter step, and
Δt是卡尔曼滤波器每个步骤间的时间差
the acceleration is a random vector with 0 mean and
加速度是一个随机向量 均值为 0
standard deviations sigma ax and sigma ay.
标准差为σax 和 σay
This vector can be decomposed into two components.
这个向量可以分解为两个分量
A four by two matrix G which does not contain random variables.
一个 4 乘 2 的矩阵 G 不包括随机变量
And a two by one matrix,
和一个 2 乘 1 的矩阵
A, which contains the random acceleration components.
A 包括随机加速度分量
Based on our noise vector, we can define now the new covariance matrix Q.
根据我们的误差向量 我们现在可以定义新的协方差矩阵 Q
The covariance matrix is defined as the expectation value of the noise vector
协方差矩阵定义为误差向量的预期值
mu times the noise vector mu transpose.
v 乘以误差向量 v 的转置
So, let's write this down.
让我们写下来
As matrix G does not contain random variables,
因为矩阵 G 不包括随机变量
we can put it outside expectation calculation.
我们可以放在预期计算的外面
This leaves us with three statistical moments.
这样 我们得到了三个统计时刻
The expectation of ax times ax, which is the variance of ax, sigma ax squared.
ax 乘以 ax 的预期 也就是 ax 的协方差 σ ax 的平方
The expectation of ay times ay which is the variance of ay, sigma ay squared,
ay 乘以 ay 的预期 也就是 ay 的协方差 σ ay 的平方
and the expectation of ax times ay, which is the covariance of ax and ay.
以及 ax 乘以 ay 的预期 也就是 ax 和 ay 的协方差
Ax and ay are assumed uncorrelated noise processes.
ax 和 ay 假定为无关联的噪过程
This means that the covariance sigma ax, ay in Q nu is 0.
这意味 Qv 中的协方差 σ ax 和 σ ay 等于 0
So after combining everything in one matrix,
因此 合并一个矩阵中所有内容后
we obtain our four by four Q matrix.
我们得到了一个 4 乘 4 的 Q 矩阵
I also want you to be aware that sometimes in the literature,
你还要注意 有时候在文献中
Q nu might be noted as Q.
Qv 可能表示为 Q
So sometimes there might be a confusion between two matrices.
因此 有时候这两个矩阵可能搞混
See below for more information.
视频下方有更多信息